frenchtoday.com 2019-05-15

# French Today Privacy Policy • French Today

**We’ll always keep your data safe and secure as well as we possibly can and we will NEVER sell your personal data to anyone.**

### **1\. The good stuff**

We will only use your data to improve your experience.

### **2\. Locked down**

We’ll protect your data like it’s our own.

### **3\. Straight talking**

We’ll always speak your language and have your back – no nonsense, no legalese, no surprises.

### **4\. No spam**

You decide what and how you hear from us. You can unsubscribe anytime you want.

### **5\. Just the essentials**

We don’t collect more info than what’s needed to improve your experience.

* * *

## Protecting Your Privacy

At French Today, we are 100% committed to protecting the privacy and security of our customers and site/apps visitors (yes, that’s you). The French Today team members are customers themselves of other internet sites – so we appreciate and respect how important privacy is. If you have any questions about how we Protect Your Privacy, drop us a line at support@frenchtoday.com For all our services, the data controller — the company that’s responsible for your privacy— is French Today.

## How we use your information

We use your information in a number of different ways — what we do depends on the information. The tables below set this out in detail, showing what we do, and why we do it.

**Your name and contact details**

**How we use your name  
& contact details** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Bill your purchases to you | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you (it’s a bit hard to send your order if we don’t use your name and contact details!)  
Send you service messages by e-mail or through our app, such as order updates | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you (so you can tell when your order is coming)  
Sending you information by email about our new products and services | To keep you up to date. We only send this with your permission  
Fraud prevention and detection | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or French Today – unfortunate, but absolutely essential  
Showing you frenchtoday.com adverts as you browse the web | So you can see our latest products and deals  
Finding out what you, and other customers, like | To ensure we are giving you what you want, and to stay relevant to your needs  
  
**Your payment information**

This means your card’s security/CVV code, don’t worry, we don’t keep them.

**How we use your payment information** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Take payment, and give refunds | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you  
Fraud prevention and detection | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or French Today – unfortunate, but absolutely essential  
  
**Your contact history with us**

What you’ve said to us — for example, in a support ticket, in an email, or on social media.

**How we use your contact history** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Provide the best customer service and support | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you, after all, you expect the best service from us  
Learn from past practices | So that, when you contact us, you get the best possible customer service  
Improve our products and offerings | So that, based on your feedback, we can make our audiobooks, content and other offers more in line with what you are looking for and need  
  
**Purchase history and saved items**

What you’ve bought and what you’ve stored in your basket for another time

**How we use your purchase history and saved items** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Sell you things | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you — if you can’t put items into the cart, you can’t buy it!  
Provide customer service and support, and handle returns | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you  
Finding out what you, and other customers, like | To ensure we are giving you what you want, and to stay ahead of the competition  
Provide access to your audiobooks within the French Today audiobook player app | Unless we know who you are and what you have access to, we can’t show you your available audiobooks  
  
**Information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our website and app**

The information you give us when you browse our site or use our app, including your IP address and device type and, if you choose to share it with us, your location data,  
as well as how you use our website and app.

**How we use information about your phone or laptop, and how you use our website and app** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Improve our website and set default options for you (such as tax rates and currency) | To give you the best possible shopping experience  
Protect our website | To prevent and detect fraud against either you or French Today – unfortunate, but absolutely essential — and to meet our legal obligations about looking after your data  
Improve our iOS, Android, Mac and Windows apps | To give you the best possible mobile and desktop app performance, to track bugs and issue reports, to figure out what features to add and improve on  
  
**Your responses to surveys, competitions,  
and promotions**

**How we use your responses to surveys, competitions, and promotions** | **Why?**  
---|---  
Run the survey, competition or promotion | We’ve got to do this to perform our contract with you — if we can’t use your entry, you can’t possibly win!  
  
You don’t have to give us any of this personal information but if you don’t, you may not be able to buy from the site, and you are unlikely to receive our optimal overall customer experience.  But that is your choice – and we respect that. We also anonymize  
and aggregate personal information (so that it does not identify you) and use it for purposes including testing our IT systems, research, data analysis, improving our site and app, and developing new products and services. We also share this information  
with some third parties that help us make sense of this data (with reports, analytics, etc..).

## Sharing your information

We do not, and will not, sell _any_ of your personal data to _any_ third party – including your name, address, email address or credit card information (which we do not keep anyway). We want to earn and maintain your trust, and we believe this is absolutely essential in order to do that. We use a select number of trusted external service providers for certain technical data analysis, processing and/or storage offerings. These service providers are carefully selected and meet high data protection and security standards. We only share information with them that is required for the services offered and we contractually bind them to keep any information we share with them as confidential and to process Personal Data only according to our instructions.

We might share your data with the following categories of companies as an essential part of being able to provide our services to you, as set out in this statement:

  1. Companies that do things to get your purchases to you, such as payment service providers, download storage companies
  2. Professional service providers, such as marketing agencies, advertising partners and website hosts, who help us run our business
  3. Credit reference agencies, law enforcement, and fraud prevention agencies, so we can help tackle fraud

We may provide third parties with aggregated but anonymized information and analytics about our customers and, before we do so, we will make sure that it does not identify you.

## Marketing messages

If you have said we can, we’ll send you marketing messages by email or via our app to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products.

**How to stop marketing messages from French Today**

You can stop receiving marketing messages from us at any time. You can do this:

  1. By clicking on the ‘unsubscribe’ link at the bottom of any marketing email
  2. By contacting our support – support@frenchtoday.com

Once you do this, we will update your profile to ensure that you don’t receive further marketing messages. Please note that, as French Today comprises several inter-connecting services, it might take a few days for all our systems to be updated, so you might get messages from us while we process your request. Stopping marketing messages will not stop critical service communications (such as order updates or where you have expressed an interest in an activity at French Today)

## Seeing adverts for French Today online

We also engage in online advertising, also to keep you aware of what we’re up to and to help you see and find our products. Like many companies, we might target French Today banners and ads to you when you are on other websites and apps. We do this using a variety of digital marketing networks and ad exchanges, and we use a range of advertising technologies like web beacons, pixels, ad tags, cookies, and mobile identifiers, as well as specific services offered by some sites and social networks, such as Facebook’s Custom Audience service. The banners and ads you see will be based on information we hold about you, or your previous use of French Today (for example the content you read on French Today) or on French Today banners or ads you have previously clicked on.

## Your information and countries outside Europe

Even though we are physically located in France, our website hosting and many of the download and marketing services we use are based in the USA. The USA is not a country in respect of which there is a European Commission decision of adequacy, and  
we protect your privacy and your rights through the use of the European Commission’s standard data protection clauses. More information about these is available here  
[http://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087](https://eur-lex.europa.eu/legal-content/en/TXT/?uri=CELEX:32010D0087)

## Keeping your information

We’ll hold on to your information for as long as you have your account, or as long as is needed to be able to provide the services to you, or (in the case of any contact you may have with our Customer Care team) for as long as is necessary to provide support-related reporting and trend analysis only. If reasonably necessary or required to meet legal or regulatory requirements, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our terms and conditions, we may also keep hold of some of your information as required, even after you have closed your account or it is no longer needed to provide the services to you.

## Your rights

You have a lot of rights relating to your personal information:

  1. The right to be informed about how your personal information is being used (like this notice)
  2. The right to access the personal information we hold about you
  3. The right to request the correction of inaccurate personal information we hold about you (although you can probably do most of this through your account panel if you are a customer)
  4. The right to request that we delete your data, or stop processing it or collecting it, in some circumstances
  5. The right to stop direct marketing messages, which you can do by unsubscribing to our emails via the unsubscribe link at the bottom and to withdraw consent for other consent-based processing at any time
  6. The right to request that we transfer or port elements of your data either to you or another service provider
  7. The right to complain to your data protection regulator

If you want to exercise your rights, have a complaint, or just have questions, please contact us via support@frenchtoday.com

## Changes to how we Protect Your Privacy

We may change this page from time to time, to reflect how we are processing your data. If we make significant changes, we will make that clear on the French Today website or other French Today services, or by some other means of contact such as email, so that you are able to review the changes before you continue to use French Today.

## Cookies

Like any other website on the internet, we use cookies when you visit our site. There are four main types of cookies – here’s how and why we use them.

  1. Site functionality cookies – these cookies allow you to navigate the site and use our features, such as “Add to Cart” and “Save for Later”.
  2. Site analytics cookies – these cookies allow us to measure and analyze how our customers use the site, to improve both its functionality and your shopping experience.
  3. Customer preference cookies – when you are browsing or shopping on frenchtoday.com, these cookies will remember your preferences (like your currency, tax rate or location), so we can make your shopping experience as seamless as possible, and more personal to you.
  4. Targeting or advertising cookies – these cookies are used to deliver ads relevant to you. They also limit the number of times that you see an ad and help us measure the effectiveness of our marketing campaigns.

By using our site, you agree to us placing these sorts of cookies on your device and accessing them when you visit the site in the future. If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, the “help” section in your browser should provide instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies. Further information about cookies can be found at https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-pecr/cookies-and-similar-technologies/ .

Please note that by deleting or disabling future cookies, your user experience may be affected and you might not be able to take advantage of certain functions of our site, and the complete French Today user experience that we pride ourselves on providing our customers.

## How to contact us

We always want to hear from our customers (especially if you feel we’ve let you down or could do better). If you:

  1. Have any questions or feedback about this notice
  2. Would like us to stop using your information
  3. Want to exercise any of your rights as set out above, or have a complaint

please don’t hesitate to contact us at [support@frenchtoday.com](mailto:support@frenchtoday.com), we will be happy to answer any questions you may have. Or if you’d absolutely like to, you can write to us at:

French Today  
63 Rue de Goas Plat  
Paimpol 22500 FRANCE

_V1.1 Last changed 20 Sept 2018  
History:  
V1.1: Added mobile app details – 20 Sept 2018  
V1.0: First iteration – 10 May 2018_
